<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"> <id>/</id><title>Gijs</title><subtitle>A blog with things I find interesting or thought someone should write them down.</subtitle> <updated>2021-05-16T23:11:22+02:00</updated> <author> <name>Gijs</name> <uri>/</uri> </author><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml"/><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-US" href="/"/> <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator> <rights> © 2021 Gijs </rights> <icon>/assets/img/favicons/favicon.ico</icon> <logo>/assets/img/favicons/favicon-96x96.png</logo> <entry><title>Adding a GUI to a Raspberry Pi running Raspberry Pi OS Lite</title><link href="/posts/adding-a-gui-to-a-raspberry-pi-with-vnc/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Adding a GUI to a Raspberry Pi running Raspberry Pi OS Lite" /><published>2021-05-16T13:00:00+02:00</published> <updated>2021-05-16T13:00:00+02:00</updated> <id>/posts/adding-a-gui-to-a-raspberry-pi-with-vnc/</id> <content src="/posts/adding-a-gui-to-a-raspberry-pi-with-vnc/" /> <author> <name>Gijs</name> </author> <category term="linux" /> <summary> You may have installed Raspberry Pi OS Lite on your Raspberry Pi, which does not ship with a GUI. If you change your mind and want a GUI after all, you can just install one. In this exercise we will install the PIXEL desktop, which is what you would get when installing the non-Lite version of Raspberry Pi OS. Preparation I assume you have a Raspberry Pi running Raspberry Pi OS Lite, and you ... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>How the Raspberry Pi enables SSH when /boot/ssh.txt is present</title><link href="/posts/how-raspberry-pi-enbales-ssh-when-boot-ssh-file-is-present/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How the Raspberry Pi enables SSH when /boot/ssh.txt is present" /><published>2021-02-28T13:00:00+01:00</published> <updated>2021-02-28T13:00:00+01:00</updated> <id>/posts/how-raspberry-pi-enbales-ssh-when-boot-ssh-file-is-present/</id> <content src="/posts/how-raspberry-pi-enbales-ssh-when-boot-ssh-file-is-present/" /> <author> <name>Gijs</name> </author> <category term="linux" /> <summary> Note on security If you decide to enable SSH, remember to change the default password! Preferably you disable password-based authentication and instead setup key-based authentication. See the official Raspberry Pi documentation on Security What does it do? In Raspberry Pi OS, SSH is disabled by default. You can manually enable SSH for example by using raspi-config. There is also a way to a... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>How the Raspberry Pi automatic file system expansion works</title><link href="/posts/raspberry-pi-file-system-resize-on-first-boot/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How the Raspberry Pi automatic file system expansion works" /><published>2021-01-09T19:00:00+01:00</published> <updated>2021-01-09T19:00:00+01:00</updated> <id>/posts/raspberry-pi-file-system-resize-on-first-boot/</id> <content src="/posts/raspberry-pi-file-system-resize-on-first-boot/" /> <author> <name>Gijs</name> </author> <category term="linux" /> <summary> When you boot Raspberry Pi OS for the first time, it performs an automatic file system expansion. This process makes sure that the file system is expanded to the size of the SD card. Because of this process, it doesn’t matter to what size SD card you write the Raspberry Pi OS image. But exactly how does this process work? As far as I can tell the Raspberry Pi OS (formerly knows as Raspbian) e... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Happy Advent of Code 2020!</title><link href="/posts/advent-of-code/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Happy Advent of Code 2020!" /><published>2020-12-01T20:00:00+01:00</published> <updated>2020-12-01T20:00:00+01:00</updated> <id>/posts/advent-of-code/</id> <content src="/posts/advent-of-code/" /> <author> <name>Gijs</name> </author> <category term="programming" /> <summary> It’s the first day of December, which means it’s time for another installment of the Advent of Code! The Advent of Code is a daily programming challenge for every day of December until Christmas. You choose how you want to solve the challenges: Python, Golang, PHP or Microsoft Excel? It’s entirely up to you! If you haven’t tried it yet, I highly recommend you give it a go. Discussing them wit... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Tips for using watch</title><link href="/posts/watch/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tips for using watch" /><published>2020-11-21T15:00:00+01:00</published> <updated>2020-11-21T15:00:00+01:00</updated> <id>/posts/watch/</id> <content src="/posts/watch/" /> <author> <name>Gijs</name> </author> <category term="linux" /> <summary> I have been using watch for some time now but only recently I found out it offers some options that make it even better! What is watch? Watch is a program that repeatedly executes a command you tell it to and shows you the output. This can be very useful when you want to observe the output of a program change over time. Useful options when using watch Watch offers a couple of neat options. ... </summary> </entry> </feed>
